(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
The Great Ancient Detective's Bizarre Investigation+
また悪い夢を見た。
Another bad dream.
陰惨な現場が日常の探偵という職業には、悪夢は付き物と言ってもいいでしょう。
Perhaps nightmares are the penalty a detective pays for being in a gruesome business.
だが、気にしている場合ではない。
But this is no time to be worrying about that.
彼女のもとに、また新たな事件が舞い込んできているからだ。
For another new case has just landed on her desk.
unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Troubled child of humanity,
unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even for those who are not human,
be happy! 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy! Don't give up, keep aiming.
生きているんだし
After all, you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you turned away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling... good grief.
古今東西 ピースピース
Past and present, here and there, peace, peace!
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 何だかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, hey, why is it
戦っているようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting someone?
うらうらうら 触れたくもない
Ura-ura-ura, I don't even want to touch
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
my past self, self, self, self.
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost that's already long dead,
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
deep inside a young and painful memory.
残念？もう居ないのに
Regret? Even though it's already gone,
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Huh? That one is better? Quite ironic, isn't it?
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self being seen through?
ナンセンス
Nonsense.
消えないレッテル
An indelible label.
yes!要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, it's a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It seems like I'm possessed,
巻き付いたまま
wrapped around me,
まだ離れない
still won't let go,
在りし日の自分
the self of days gone by.
undead
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead yet.
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive means to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて
Don't be satisfied
満足するなよ
with being unhappy.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to try to be happy!
この世 この世は
This world, this world is
奇怪 奇怪ファンタジー
a strange, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will an ogre or a snake appear next?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting, encountering, the story finally begins.
さあ人か化物か
Come on, are you human or a monster?
閑話休題
Anyway, let's get back to the point.
ピースピース
Peace, peace!
past & future
can't change the past
run for the future
カットイン
Cut-in!
何だかどうして
Why, why is it?
未来になんぞ
In the future,
何の希望もない期待出来ない
there's no hope, I can't expect anything,
ような気がして
I feel like that.
もう随分生きている
I've been alive for a long time,
既視感とテンプレで食傷
fed up with déjà vu and clichés.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's no sign of any wonderful event.
残念
Regret.
積んだ経験の因果
The cause and effect of accumulated experience,
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
formless myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want stimulation.
飽きちゃった
I'm bored of it.
慣れちゃった
I'm used to it,
なんて
or so I say.
整っていくガイダンス
Guidance that keeps getting adjusted,
増えるコンプライアンス
increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
it feels like it's being covered up.
吸い尽くして
Sucking it all up,
あれもこれもどれも
this and that and everything
同じ味がする
tastes the same.
and now it all just tastes the same
UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
Still alive, time is a chain of your own path
いつの世も 過去も未来も今にあるんだ
In any era, your past and your future are in this very moment
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the life you're set upon, and truthfully keep moving on
目指せハッピーエンド
Go for that happy ending
UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前に言ってるんだ
Still alive, I'm telling this to you, now
幸せを諦めてしまうな
So never give up on pursuing your happiness
人で在れ
And keep being human
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Cause being numb to suffering, always enduring everything
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
It's almost as if you're dead, a lot of corpses undead, oh
unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
unhappy? If you're dealing with a lotta woes
unlucky? 人成らざる者も
unlucky? Then you gotta listen very close
be happy! 弛まず目指せよ
be happy! Keep on trying, never give up
生きているんだろ
Be aware that you're alive
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Drowning deep in unhappiness, or seizing that true happiness
そう全部全部お前だ
It's on you, on you, it's all on you
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象
Universal, all embracing all creations
ピースピース
peace, peace yeah
past & future
can't change the past
run for the future
人のあるところにいつも憂い事
Where people gather and go, you'll find all worries and woes
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Oh, you gotta live on, through this tale of monsters everywhere
これ、誰の写真なんですか？
Who's this a picture of anyway?
いま調べている事件の被害者だよ。
The victim from a case I'm working.
あっ、報酬はいつもの値段でいいよね？
Anyway, you're charging the standard fee, right?
悪いけど今回はツケにしといて
Sorry, but can you put it on my tab?
でも前回もツケって言ってましたよね...
But you put the last one on your tab too...
じゃあイナは特別に...1回だけタダで依頼を受けてあげるから。
Maybe we could do a trade then? I'll solve one case for you for free.
それよりも...歌がいいな〜。
Oooorrr... I'll trade you for a song~
はい？
Huh?
だって！アーニャさん最近ずっと怖い顔してますよ。
Come on! You've been so serious lately.
たまには息抜きしないと。
You gotta get loose sometimes.
私と1曲歌ってくれたら、絵は差し上げます。どうですか？
So one song with me, and you get to keep the picture. That's the deal~
そこまで言うなら...歌ってやるか！
If that's what you want, then alright!
大きな白いキャンバスに 虚構のコラージュを貼るよ
On a large white canvas, I'll paste a collage of fiction
どこからでもキレイに映る 誇張された天使が居たよ
An exaggerated angel was there, beautifully reflected from any angle
まだ 人 歪んだ 正しくなくても見えた
Still, the person is distorted; even if it wasn't correct, it was visible
生きるため立ち寄った美術館のセザンヌに
In Cezanne, at the art museum I dropped by to survive
なんもわかんないな
I don't understand anything
私 知らずにいても描けた
I could draw it even without knowing yet
赤 ずっと塗り込んだ
I painted it red for a long time
ばか きっとそうだった
Fool, surely it was like that
一人 筆を掻いた
I wielded the brush alone
けど そこが良いな
But I like it that way
くだらない線だなぁ そのまま
What a silly line, just like that
切って 貼って 変わって
Cut it, paste it, change it
泣いて 見えた 青 青
Crying, I saw blue, blue
ララララララ 笑うように 浮いた 浮いた 泡
La-la-la-la-la-la, floating, floating bubbles as if laughing
ギュって 裂いて から
After tearing it tightly
ギュって 泣いた から
Because I cried tightly
泣いて 泣いた から から
Because I cried, cried...
ララララララ 嘆く壁に 描いた パブロ ピカソ
La-la-la-la-la-la, Pablo Picasso, painted on a lamenting wall
なぜか私のことだなって眺めちゃったよ。
For some reason, I stared at it thinking it was about me.
これが欲しいなって感じたら...
If I feel like I want this...
お姉さんの絵を勝ち取る！なんてね♪
I'll win over the lady's painting! Just kidding~
ドッペルゲンガーがじっと見てたよ
The doppelganger was staring intently.
二番 嘘を 重ねたら
If I layer second lies,
本物の意味あるのかな
Is there any real meaning to it?
私怨 ずっと 抱いたまま
Still harboring personal grudges,
飾り落ちて床で死んでた
The decorations fell and died on the floor.
血 青 ずっと 塗り込んだ
Blood, blue, I kept painting it...
やっぱ ずっと 良かった
As expected, it was always good.
卑しい線だな 今も
What a vulgar line, even now.
切って 貼って 変わって
Cut it, paste it, change it
咲いて 散った 花 花
The flowers that bloomed and scattered
ララララララ 笑うように 見えた 見えた から
La-la-la-la-la-la, because it looked like it was laughing
ギュって 裂いた から
Because I tore it tightly
ギュって 泣いた から
Because I cried tightly
泣いて 泣いた から から
Because I cried, cried...
ララララララ 嘆く壁に 描いた パブロ ピカソ
La-la-la-la-la-la, Pablo Picasso, painted on a lamenting wall
私 嘘の ピカソ
I am a fake Picasso
やっと来た。
Finally.
こんな不気味な場所で待たせないでほしいんだけど。
This is a creepy place to make someone wait.
現場を調べたらKFPの近くに寄るから、店の近くで待っててって言ったのに。
I told you I'd come to the nearby KFP after investigating the crime scene.
そんなの無理！
Not a chance!
アンタと話すだけでもイヤなのに、話してるところを人に見られたりしたらそれこそ最悪。
It's bad enough I have to talk to you. I don't want others to be around to see it.
そんなアンタが手を貸してくれるなんて意外だけどね。
I'm surprised you're willing to cooperate in the first place.
それは...例の殺人事件以降、いろいろ妙なことが起こってるの。
Yeah, well, ever since the murder, weird things have been happening.
アンタが解決してくれるなら、こうやって会うのもやむなしよ。
I figure if you can help solve it, then it's worth the trouble of meeting with you.
イヤだけど。
Just barely.
妙なことが起こってる？
What weirdness?
『人の形をした黒い影が見えた』って報告が、うちの従業員からちょくちょく出てるの。
Some of my employees have been complaining about seeing a shadowy figure.
話によれば、最初は夢の中にそれが現れたんだけど、今は起きてる時も見ええるって――
They say it started with bad dreams, but now some are seeing it even when they're—
アーニャ！
Anya!
だ...大丈夫。それより...
I'm... fine, don't worry about me.
これ見て。
Look at this.
まったくもう、アンタはいつも大げさすぎ...ん？
Hmph. 'Course. You're just always being overly dramatic... huh?
おかしいな。現場の証拠品は警察が全部回収したはずなのに。
Weird. I figured the cops would have already collected all the evidence.
この近くに住んでるKFPの従業員で、被害者のことを知ってる者は？
Did any of your employees who live nearby know the victim?
いない。
Nope.
分かった。新しい情報が入ったらまた教えて。
Alright. Let me know if you hear anything else.
ちょっと待った！
Wait!
それだけ？
That's it?
私の時間を奪っておいてタダで帰るつもり？
You're not even gonna compensate me for my time?
従業員のためかと思いきや、結局カネかい。
I thought you were doing this to help your employees.
タダ働きはしない主義なの。
I'm still a businesswoman.
いま持ち合わせがないんだけど、代わりに歌で支払うっていうのはどう？
Well, I don't have any cash on me, but I can pay you in song.
ウソでしょ？
Seriously?
歌うの？アンタと？
You think I'd want to sing? With you?
イナは歌で喜んでくれたけどなー。
Ina accepted payment in song.
ただ、イナと歌うのは楽しいけど、
But then, singing with her is fun.
But then, singing with Ina is fun,
キアラと歌ってもなぁ...
...but with you...
それどういう意味？
What's that supposed to mean?
私の歌じゃダメってこと？
You don't think my singing is good enough?
やってやろうじゃないの！ほら、さっさと歌うよ！
Let's do this! Come on, let's sing right now!
全部全部アンタのせいだ
All, all, it's all your fault.
反吐が出るくらいにウザったいわ
It makes me want to throw up, it's so annoying.
何かに縋って諂って
Clinging to something, flattering someone,
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was a fool to have expectations.
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
An eight-way beauty that serves to please,
それ故にアンチな一生gimme
That's why you'll get a lifelong anti, gimme.
浅いキャパシティ まいどおおきに
Shallow capacity, thanks as always,
つまる とこ 人生 ずっと 地味
In the end, your life is always plain.
｢憎たらしい！｣ ｢痛々しい！｣
'Hatable!' 'Painful!'
無視出来ないのが一層
Not being able to ignore it makes it even more
腹立たしい 苛立たしい
Frustrating, irritating,
そろそろ飽きた 自画自賛に
I'm sick of your self-praise.
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of like is apathy
≒繋がれた証
≒ proof of being connected.
切り離せない関係
An inseparable relationship,
逸らしてしまいたいわ
I want to break free.
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is what you call hate speech,
匿名性の声明を生命に載せてんだ
I'm putting anonymous statements into life.
鳴り止まないサイレン 近づく度に痙攣
Unending siren, cramping every time it approaches,
赤信号にずっと従順です
I'm always obedient to the red light.
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Basically, how I see you,
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
I hate you, hate you, hate you, hate you, hate you!
omg情けない最早
OMG, how pathetic, already,
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
Bye-bye, bye-bye, I want to say bye.
脳内も予測不能故に
My brain is also unpredictable, so
解解解解解は無い
There's no, no, no, no, no solution.
どうだい？ アタシのコト アナタ
How about it? How do you see me?
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
Have you come to hate me, hate me, hate me, hate me, hate me?
あァ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, a hundred harms and no benefit, nothing not see,
もしタラレバ並べても ニコチンだし
Even if you line up the ifs, it's just nicotine.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス 凡ミス
The result of approaching with 'I miss you' is a clumsy mistake, a clumsy mistake,
センキュー 反面教師
Thank you, counter-teacher,
後味一生消えてくんないわ
This aftertaste will never disappear in my lifetime.
よしよし いい子ね
Good, good, good boy,
笑顔振り撒きパラパラ いい子ね
Smiling, scattering smiles, what a good boy.
だけど だけど その本性は？
But, but, what's your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？
Can't you even distinguish good from evil?
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Wrapped up in an environment that surrounds you with a point-deduction system,
生涯、痛い！痛い！痛い！も聞かれないわ！って
In your lifetime, no one will even hear you cry 'Painful! Painful! Painful!'
当然の報いにクラっちゃった
I got hit by the natural retribution,
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors,
実のところ依存は両辺です
In reality, dependency is two-sided,
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
Even if you shut down, it clings to you,
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
My own weakness is shameful.
全部全部アンタのせいって
All, all, it's all your fault,
反吐が出るくらいに止まんないわ
It doesn't stop to the point of throwing up.
いっその事 切り離せた方が楽なのに な
If only I could just cut it off, it would be easier.
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Basically, how I see you,
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
I hate you, hate you, hate you, hate you, hate you!
omg情けない最早
OMG, how pathetic, already,
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
Bye-bye, bye-bye, I want to say bye.
脳内も予測不能故に
My brain is also unpredictable, so
解解解解解は無い
There's no, no, no, no, no solution.
どうだい？ アタシのコト アナタ
How about it? How do you see me?
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
Have you come to hate me, hate me, hate me, hate me, hate me?
あァ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, a hundred harms and no benefit, nothing not see,
もしタラレバ並べても ニコチンだし
Even if you line up the ifs, it's just nicotine.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス 凡ミス
The result of approaching with 'I miss you' is a clumsy mistake, a clumsy mistake,
センキュー 反面教師
Thank you, counter-teacher,
後味一生消えてくんないわ
This aftertaste will never disappear in my lifetime.
えっ、もう誰なの？
Ugh, who is it now?
はーい
Come in.
アーニャ、ヤッホー。
Hey Anya, hello!
って、大丈夫そう？
Wait, are you doing okay?
なんか顔色悪いね。
You look kind of... not great.
大丈夫、じゃないかもね。
I'm okay... actually, maybe not.
ちょっと横になった方がいいんじゃない？
Shouldn't you lie down for a bit?
周りをぐるぐる走ってあげるから、わための数を数えるといいよ。
Lie down, and I'll run in circles so you can count me~
心配かけてごめん。
Sorry for making you worry.
でも、今寝たらダメなんだ。
But I can't sleep right now.
なぜなら、あともうちょっとでこの事件を解決できそうなんだから！
Because I'm so close to solving this case!
そう？
Really?
そう、かも。
Maybe...
そうじゃないかも。
Maybe not.
わかんないけど、とりあえずヒントは揃ったんだ。
I don't know, but I have all the hints...
ほな、難しいか。
Then that's going to be tough.
わため先輩、程々にしておきましょう。
Watame-senpai, let's leave her be.
わためは悪くないよねぇ？
Watame did nothing wrong, right?
これが事件を解く鍵なんだ。
This is the key to solving the case.
探偵の直感がそう言ってる。
My detective intuition is telling me so.
でも、DNA鑑定では何もわからなかった。
But the DNA test didn't show anything.
じゃあ、これは何なんだ？
Then, what is this?
これは何なんだ？！
What is this?!
その布でそんなにお困りなら...
If you're so troubled by that cloth...
じゃ、わためが食べてあげる！
Then, Watame will eat it for you!
ねえ、アーニャ、それちょっと見せてくれる？
Hey Anya, can you let me see that for a second?
この布についてわかったことはあるけど...
I found out something about this cloth, but...
うーん、それを教えたら、ちょっと休憩しない？
Hmm, if I tell you, will you take a little break?
一旦、仕事の手は止めて...
Stop working for a bit...
私たちと遊ぼうよ！
and hang out with us!
じゃあ、一緒に歌でも歌う？
Then, do you want to sing together?
この街では、情報は歌で買うものみたいだし。
In this town, it seems information is bought with song.
おー、楽しそう！
Oh, that sounds fun!
オッケー！
Okay!
その布には、魔力の痕跡を感じるんだ。
I can feel a trace of magic on that cloth.
そんなバカな。
That can't be true.
忘れたの？アイリスはネフィリム。
Hey, I'm a nephilim, remember?
魔力を感じ取るなんてお手の物。
We get a bonus to detect magic!
あれ？アーニャもこの布が怪しいと思ってたんじゃないの？
Wait... you already had your suspicions about the cloth, didn't you?
そうだけどさ。でも、殺人事件と超常現象なんて混ぜたら駄目なやつでしょ？
Yeaaah... but supernatural stuff happening in a murder case? They're not supposed to mix.
そう？でもそういうアニメとかドラマも...
Really? But in some shows—
まあまあ、物騒な話はそのくらいにして、
Enough murder talk.
みんなで歌っちゃおう！
Let's sing—
この路地を抜けろ make now
Let's take this alley, make now
僕ら覚醒アップデート ey
We get an arousal update, ey!
ギラギラ光らせた
Shining so bright and glittery
いいな いいな そのカラット
How nice, how nice, that carat!
目立っちゃうな 自然に視線を独り占め
Naturally hogging all the attention!
この手口は盗めない
No one can steal this trick
答えなら 好きなだけが極まってく
If it's the answer, doing what I love is reaching the peak
一秒前 完全アップデート
A second ago was a complete update
不安ぐっばい 自分以外は敵じゃない
Goodbye anxiety, nobody's my enemy but myself
お利口御無用 指を立てろ
No need to be a good kid, raise your finger
揺れろ運命
Let destiny shake
あたしらしい ultra c
My own style of Ultra C
今 その感情を燃料に持ち込む延長線へ全能
Taking those emotions as fuel onto the home stretch, I'm omnipotent
嗚呼 体が
Ah, my body...
この生き様で make some noise
Make some noise with this way of life!
見舞う gotta go メディカルボイス
I'll visit, gotta go, a medical voice
宿した熱狂は伝達する 真っ向から着弾
The passion harbored spreads, hitting directly from the front
もらうわ 大歓声
I'll take the huge cheers!
burn out na na uh !
Burn out na na uh!
what i want to touch down
燃やせ革命アップデート
Burn up, revolution update!
go all out
僕が覚醒逆転 ey
My awakening turnaround, ey!
ひとりきりじゃ just kidding
On my own? Just kidding
君とだから dreaming
Because I'm with you, I'm dreaming
間違いだらけ 勘違いもして
Full of mistakes, even making misunderstandings
ときめきを retake
Retake the excitement
失っても 尚コンティニュー
Even if lost, still continue
支払った代償の自分
The self that paid the price
あの日に uh してないわけない後悔
On that day, uh... there's no way I don't regret
胸に飾れ 前向き直せ 唱えて
Decorate your chest, face forward, and chant
諦め悪いって？ 信じてくれ
Giving up easily? Believe in me
青く燃ゆる 僕は炎
Burning blue, I am the flame
時は経てど 恋うは心
Though time passes, the heart still yearns
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ あたしだ
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it? It's me!
さあ お任せ burn out na na uh !
Now leave it to me, burn out na na uh!
ha ~
抜ける茨で make some noise
Through the thorns, make some noise!
有終の美 get up !
The perfect ending, get up!
臆した逆境に下克上 とうとう役満
A revolt against intimidating adversity, finally a Yakuman!
あげるわ 大団円！
I'll give you a grand finale!
burn out na na uh !
Burn out na na uh!
what i want to touch down
燃やせ革命アップデート hey
Burn up, revolution update, hey!
go all out
僕が覚醒逆転 ey
My awakening turnaround, ey!
以上がこちらで調べた情報です。いかがですか？
So that's everything I've got so far. What do you think?
ここは大空警察。数々の難事件を解決してきた優秀な警察から今回の事件に関する更なる情報を得るべく、探偵は警察署を訪れていた。
And so, here she visits the Oozora Police. With their stellar track record of solving mysterious cases like this one easily, she hopes that they can give her some leads.
だから、事件の捜査は、我々プロに任せとけばいいんだよ。
I think you should leave the investigating to the professionals.
何？被害者の服に魔力の痕跡があったって？
I mean, magical residue on the victim's clothing?
そうだ！そんなバカな話があるか！
Yes! That is very silly!
こいつ、次、自分自身が凶器かもしれないとか言い出すんじゃないですか、署長？
Next, she's going to tell me that SHE'S actually involved and might be the murder weapon.
それだ！
Wait, that's it!
はぁ？
Huh?
こいつ今、自分が凶器だって自白した？
Did she just confess to being the murder weapon?
よ、よく分かんないっす。ボクが言ったのはただの冗談で…
I-I don't really know. I was just joking about that...
もしかしてボク、無意識のうちに真実をつかんでいたのか！？
What if I subconsciously knew the truth this whole time?!
お前天才か！？
Are you a genius?!
おや、これはいよいよ事件解決…になってしまうのか？
Oh my, could this possibly mean the case is solved?
事件解決しちゃった！
I solved the case!
違う違う、私は凶器じゃないですよ。
No, no. I'm not the murder weapon.
異議あり！さっき自白しただろ！
OBJECTION! You already confessed!
私が言いたいのは、この事件にはまた別の古代兵器が関わっているかもしれないということ。
What I mean is, maybe there was another ancient weapon involved.
だから布に魔力が残っていたんだ。
That would explain the magical residue on the cloth.
なんだ、そういうことか…
I guess that makes sense.
ボクが事件を解決できたと思ったのに…
But I wanted to solve the case...
まあ次がんばれよ。
You'll solve the next one.
でもなぁ、現場の近くで変なものを見たっていう報告も届いてるんだ。
But we've also gotten reports of people seeing strange things near the murder scene.
その魔力の痕跡とやらが超常的な力によるものだって言うなら…
If the involvement of something supernatural explains the magical residue,
変な幻覚が見えた人がいるのもそいつの影響ってこと？
does it also cover those weird visions?
それはまだ分かりませんが、謎は必ず解いてみせましょう。
I'm not sure yet, but I'm going to find out.
じゃあうちの捜査資料を持っていっていいよ。
Then we will give you our case file to help out.
民間人にあげちゃダメっすよ！
You can't give that to a civilian!
でもこいつさぁ、なんか天才の匂いしね？
But she seems like a genius, doesn't she?
さっきはボクのこと天才って言ったじゃないですかぁ…
But that was my thing...
どんな情報でも助かりますよ。
Any information you have would be useful.
ただし！資料が欲しいなら、タダというわけにはいかんな！
Fiiine! But if you want our files, then we need something in return.
これ、また歌う流れですか？
Could that thing be, perhaps, a song?
おれは しらない なにも しらない
I don't know, I don't know anything.
なにも みてない だれも みてない
I haven't seen anything, no one has seen anything.
そらを みても みえない よるの
Even if I look at the sky, I can't see the night's...
かけた つきに うさぎ
...waning moon's rabbit.
これは なんだ それが なにか？
What is this? What of it?
ここは たのし それで よろし
Here it is fun, and that's fine.
はしる にげる にがす そらす
Run, flee, let loose, look away,
月の 欠けた 場所へ
to the place where the moon has waned.
あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら
Alara, alara, alara, alara, alara...
もうそう とめどなく
My delusions are endless.
そうぞう とがめなく
My creations are blameless.
しょうどう おさまらず
My impulses are relentless.
なぜか なぜか なぜか なぜかしら？
For some reason, why is that?
最悪だ！ 公序良俗を剥いで脱いで踊れ！
It's the worst! Strip away public decency and dance!
いや最低か！ なんでなんでつって なんかなんか高鳴って
Or is it the absolute lowest! Why, oh why, is my heart thumping?
最悪だ！ どうもこうもしねぇよ勝手にしやがれ！
It's the worst! I don't give a damn, do whatever you want!
いや最低か！ いやーもうほんと 最悪だ！だ！だ！だ！だ！
Or is it the absolute lowest! Man, it's really the worst!
ねても さめても つきまとう
Asleep or awake, it haunts me.
みえぬ いしきの うらがわに
Behind my unseen consciousness...
おおきく あいた くろいあな
...is a gaping black hole.
わかる わかる わかる
I get it, I get it, I get it.
ゆるす ゆるせん ゆるす ゆるせ
Forgive, unforgivable, forgive, forgive!
かわいい えへへ むふふ こわい
Cute, ehehe, mufufu, scary.
りんご ごりら らくご こちら なくだ だぼら らまだん
Apple, gorilla, rakugo, here, camel, nonsense, ramadan.
わたしたち ぜったいに みてません
We absolutely didn't see anything!
しってません きいてません しったこっちゃありません
We didn't know, we didn't hear, we couldn't care less!
光をいっしっ 影にひとつ。 許されざる思考を 当てはまらない異常を 包んで生きていこうじゃありませんか！
Why don't we wrap up our unforgivable thoughts and unclassifiable anomalies, and live on?
こうどう なももたず
Action, without even a name.
きょうそう いみもなく
Compete, without any meaning.
えいがい じこまんぞく
Movies, pure self-satisfaction.
だから だから だから だからな！
So, so, so, that's why!
最高だ！ 脳が効化してんだ ぶっ壊して叫べ！
It's the best! My brain is melting down, break it and scream!
いや最高か！ なんでなんでつって なんかまこまこはしゃいじゃって
Or is it the absolute best! Why, oh why, am I frolicking around?
最高だ！ 豪気豪気で結構 勝手に生きたれ！
It's the best! Being audacious is great, live however you want!
いや最高か！ いやーもうほんと最高だ！だ！だ！だ！だ！
Or is it the absolute best! Man, it's really the best!
むかし むかしの おもいつき
An idea from once upon a time.
むいみ むいみの ひとだかり
A meaningless, meaningless crowd of people.
むじゃき むてきの うまれつき
Innocent and invincible by birth.
それが それが それが
That is, that is, that is...
むせきにん しゅうごうたい
...irresponsible collection.
あんたも わたしも かんけいない むせきにん しゅうごうたい
You, me, none of us are involved, irresponsible collection.
たのしく やってりゃ もんだいない
As long as we're having fun, there's no problem.
おれは しらない なにも しらない なにも みてない なにも
I don't know, I don't know anything, I haven't seen anything...
超常的な力が殺人事件に関わっている？
A supernatural occurrence, happening in a murder case?
いやいやそんな、ねえ？
That's just unbelievable.
にわかには信じがたいが、今の手がかりから推理するとそう言うことになる。
She had a hard time believing it, but all the hints said otherwise.
まだパズルのピースがピタリとはまらないこの不思議で奇妙な事件。
Still, there were pieces of this puzzle that refused to fit,
探偵は信頼できる情報源に頼ることにした。
so the detective turned to a reliable source for help.
あっ、来てくれたー
Hey, I'm glad—
…なんで君達まで？
...And why are you guys also here?
ゼータが来るって聞いたから、アーニャにちょっかいかけてやろうと思って！
We heard Zeta was coming over, and decided to bug ya!
はいはい。
Yes, yes. I see.
もー！つれないなぁ。
Aww, come on!
それはそうと…ゼータ、何か掴めた？
Anyway, Zeta, did you find anything?
もちろん！優秀なシークレットエージェントなので！
Of course! I'm not an elite secret agent for nothing.
イナの描いた似顔絵と大空警察の資料から、被害者の身元を特定できたよ。
Between the portrait from Ina and the files from the Oozora Police, I've been able to positively ID the murder victim.
でも…ちょっと変なんだよね。
But... what I found is weird.
変？
How so?
被害者の履歴を調べたところ、その人物は何百年も前の時代の人だったんだ。
Well, when I investigated their history, I found that they actually lived centuries ago.
でもその人物が、数日前に死体で発見された。話がつながらないよ。
So how they were also somehow murdered just days ago... it doesn't make any sense.
アーニャからもらった情報に間違いがあったとか？
Did you perhaps confuse your information? Or...
なるほど。やっとつながってきた。
Actually, things are finally starting to make sense.
え？
Oh?
一人の被害者が、過去と現在で二度死んだこととなる。
A victim caught between two times.
誰かが時間と次元をねじ曲げて、そんな状況を作り出した。
One who died in two different ways.
なかなかできることじゃない…
Not many exist who can cause time and dimensions to warp in a way to make that possible...
でも君なら可能でしょ。
...but you're one of them.
さすがは名探偵。
Well done, detective.
ちょっと時間がかかりすぎかな。
Took you long enough.
危なくネタばらしするとこだった。
I was this close to telling ya the whole thing.
レイネが書いてくれた、この匿名の手紙もいいヒントになったよ。
You helped enough with this "anonymous" letter about the murder.
えっ、バレてた？
O-oh, you figured out that was me?
書き方のクセで分かる。
I recognized your writing style.
待って、どういうこと？ムーナと被害者にどんな関係があるの？
W-wait, I don't get it. What does Moona have to do with the victim?
ムーナは、別の時空で殺された遺体を我々がいるこの時空へ移動させたんだ。
She took a murder victim from another space and time, and moved them into our dimension.
ゼータが特定した人物は、この世界線における同一人物ってこと。
The one you IDed was this universe's version of the same person.
なるほど…？でもどうしてそんなことを？
Uh... okay. But then why?
理由も気になるけど、それより確かめたいことがある。
That is an important question, but there's one I want answered even more.
ムーナが…私にああの夢を見せたの？
Are you... responsible for my dreams?
それは違う。
No.
あなたがあの夢を見ていることを知って、私はあの夢が生まれる根源を調べてみた。
After I learned about your dreams, I used my powers to search for the source of them.
そして見つけたのが、次元の向こう側から声を届けようとする魂。
I found a spirit reaching out from time and dimensions.
私はその魂のために橋渡しをしてあげただけ…
All I've done is try to help them by making the bridge a little easier...
私も手伝ったよ！というか、私のアイデア。
With my help! I mean, it was my idea...
そう。
True.
ただやり方が悪かったのか、アーニャの見たものが他の人にも見えちゃったみたい。
Though doing this way has caused some of what you've been experiencing to leak to other people.
巻き込んだKFPの従業員には後でお詫びしなきゃ…
We're going to have to apologize to the KFP workers...
でもその魂が、どうして私に声を届けようとしてるの？
But why is the spirit reaching out to me of all people?
それは私に訊くことじゃないね。私が話すべきことじゃない。
It wouldn't be right for me to answer those questions. It's not my story to tell.
あの魂に心を開いてあげて。それだけでいい。
Open yourself up to the spirits, and they'll do the rest.
心をもっと開く方法なら知ってるよ！
I got a way to make yourself more open to spirits!
それって歌？
Is it through song?
え？なんで分かったの？
Huh? How'd you know?
まあ、勘かな…
Lucky guess...
思い返していた 思い出の中で泣いていた
I was looking back, crying in my memories
不確かな夢と孤独を 抱えて笑ってた
Holding onto uncertain dreams and loneliness, I laughed
この痛みも傷も いたいけな瞳も
This pain, these wounds, and even those innocent eyes
無に帰してしまいそうな 焦りと不安が滲んで 涙に飲まれてしまう
Seeming to return to nothingness, impatience and anxiety seep in, drowning in tears
誰一人欠けることはない ちぐはぐだった
Not a single one is missing, we were mismatched
僕らの想いが 音になって繋ぐ
Our feelings become sound, connecting us
こだましていく 忘れないよう
Echoing out, so as not to forget
かき鳴らした日々を
The days we played loudly
あの日僕らは 間違いじゃないと知る
That day we learned it wasn't a mistake
閉ざしてしまいこんだ 一閃の光探して
Searching for a flash of light we locked away
君の声を聴かせて
Let me hear your voice
ここにいるって
Saying that you're here
叫んでくれよ
Shout it out!
その手を離さないで
Don't let go of that hand
世界に僕だけが...
As if only I in the world...
だったよな
...wasn't it?
暗闇のなかで 立ち止まり 手放してしまう
Stopping in the darkness, and letting go
心が通じ合えない孤独感を 押し殺してしまうなら
If I end up crushing this feeling of isolation when our hearts can't connect...
一人でいた方が 楽に生きられたかな
...I wonder if it would have been easier to live alone?
憧れ 理想に 強く惹かれる感情が
This feeling strongly drawn towards yearning and ideals...
僕らを引き寄せてしまうのなら
...if it draws us together...
応えて
...then answer me!
狂わせて
Drive me crazy...
まだ終わっちゃいないんだ 僕らの延長戦を
It's not over yet, our extra time...
この音が途切れるまで
...until this sound cuts out!
子供の頃に描いたヒーロー
The hero I pictured when I was a kid...
君の出番が 待っている
...your turn to shine is waiting!
震わせて 忘れないよう 掻き鳴らした日々を
Make me tremble, so I won't forget the days we strummed away
あの日
On that day,
僕らは 間違っていなかったんだと知る
we'll know we weren't wrong.
閉ざして しまい込んだ 一閃の光 探して
Searching for the flash of light we locked and shut away...
君の声を聴かせて
...let me hear your voice!
ここにいるって叫んでくれよ
Shout out that you're right here!
その手を離さないで
Don't let go of that hand!
魂に心を開け？簡単に言ってくれる。
Opening up to the spirit? That was a tall order.
探偵になる前の彼女の人生において、他者に心を開くのは危険な行為だった。
In her life before being a detective, opening up to someone was dangerous.
今でもその本能は変わらない。
That instinct still lingers.
結局何も進展はなかった。
This was getting her nowhere.
謎はまだ残っているが、彼女はここのところ無理が続いていた。
She still had questions she needed answered, but maybe she had wound herself up too much.
少し休まなければ。
She needed a break.
Hello everyone!
I'm Hatsune Miku!
Well, that's what everyone seems to think, but secretly I'm...
Miku-chan!
Anya-chan!
一緒に歌おう！
Let's sing together!
I wake up to a call, put my frilly outfit on now
It's time I open up my eyes and start the day
I combat till the dawn, until every villain's gone, wah!
Bearing through the pain, I try to be brave
As long as you can stay happy, I'm okay. I'm not gonna bend, ha!
I can be a cure for peace in your heart, and I'll play as a nurse healing you every day
Your smile is enough to heal all my aches, all in a cute band-aid
If you're feeling pain, call my name, I'll be by your side 'til I see your smile beam bright again
うりゃ おい！ うりゃ おい！ う～ ファイター！ スーパーパワフルミクちゃーん！
Urya oi! Urya oi! Oooo fighter! Super powerful Miku-chan!
うりゃ おい！ うりゃ おい！ う～ サイバー！ ミク ミク ミク go !
Urya oi! Urya oi! Oooo cyber! Miku miku miku go!
あぁ、眠いよ～
Ah, I'm sleepy...
あっ！
Ah!
夢だった？！
It was a dream?!
知った。
I knew.
救いのない形だった僕の声は
My voice was of a helpless form
知った。
I knew.
狂いのない赤い血が流れているんだ<
Flawless red blood is flowing
ただただ襲い来る影ばかり
Only the shadows constantly assailing me
目背けて抗う言葉立ち上がれないよ風
Turning away, resisting words, the wind won't let me stand
赤く光る場所へ裸足で駆け出したら
Running barefoot toward the place shining red
ただ膝を抱えている君がいた
You were there, just holding your knees
だからEncount! 悲劇ぶった天国へ
So, Encount! To a heaven acting like a tragedy
不甲斐ない瞳きっとあの日見つめた君のせいだ
My pathetic eyes, surely it's because of you who stared back that day
早く、早く、早く、早く
Faster, faster, faster, faster
早く、早く、早く、早く身を委ねて
Faster, faster, faster, faster, surrender your body
淡い、淡い、水面の向こうへと
To the other side of the faint, faint water surface
知った。
I knew.
救いのない熱を持った僕の炎夏
My midsummer heat held a helpless warmth
知った。
I knew.
狂いのない貴方の目は醜かった
Your flawless eyes were hideous
酷く、酷く、酷く、酷く
Terribly, terribly, terribly, terribly
酷く、酷く、酷く、酷く...
Terribly, terribly, terribly, terribly...
呆然としてるその顔に触れてみたかった
I wanted to try touching that dumbfounded face
だからEncount! 喜劇ぶった天国へ
So, Encount! To a heaven acting like a comedy
奪い合う瞳 乾いた
Clashing eyes, parched...
崩れた 貴方のせいで
They crumbled all because of you.
はやく はやく はやく はやく はやく はやく
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry...
ねえ、教えて
Hey, tell me,
深い 深い 秘密の向こうへと
beyond the deep, deep secret...
antipathy world
不甲斐ない 日々を重ねた
Overlapping these disappointing days,
うつむいた 君のせいで
all because of you hanging your head.
はやく はやく はやく はやく はやく はやく
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry...
ねえ、教えて
Hey, tell me,
甘い 甘い 嘘の向こうへと
beyond the sweet, sweet lie...
白い光を見つめていると
Staring into the white light...
急な痛みに襲われる
...a sudden pain washes over me.
僕が 私を 保っていられなくなること
Losing my grip on who I am...
それこそが この小さな楽器が証明している
...is what this small instrument proves.
はじめに、安堵する君が見たい
First, I want to see you relieved.
つぎに、期待したい
Next, I want to hope.
この場所で戦いなど起こっていない。
There was no major battle here.
少なくともこの世界線では...
At least not in this timeline...
だが探偵には分かっていた。彼女が見たものは決して夢ではないことを。
But the detective knows what she saw was no dream.
心の中にはまだ殺戮の匂いが漂っている。
The smell of the carnage still lingers in her mind.
かつての彼女にまとわりついていた、あの匂い。
It's a scent that was, at one time, so familiar to her.
探偵としての生活も今では順調だが、そうでなければあの匂いからは離れることができなかったでしょう。
That stench would still linger on her if the detective's life didn't take a turn for the better.
今でも... あの頃の日々がリアルな夢のようにまとわりつく。
Even now... her days felt more like the real dream.
終わるべくして終わったおとぎ話。
A fairytale. Maybe one that deserved to end.
どこまで行っても彼女は、生まれ持った本質から逃れることはできない。
Because, at the end of the day, she can never run away from her nature.
それでも今は違う。今の彼女には仲間がいる。
But she's not just that anymore. She has friends to thank for that.
それが、別の世界線の彼女とは違う点なのかもしれない。
Maybe that was what separated her from the other version.
もしかしたらあの子は、幸せに生きることのできた世界線があったのだろうかと、
And, maybe... that version of herself just wanted a ray of hope,
そんな一筋の希望を求めていたのだろうか。
to know that there was one timeline where things worked out.
そしてその幸せな世界線というのは、ここではないまた別の世界線のことかもしれない...
Or perhaps this was never about the detective...
考えが頭を巡るものの、答えが出ることはない。
so many thoughts run amok inside her head, but they're forever left unanswered.
何にせよ、探偵は自身の血塗られた過去を忘れることはないでしょう。
Whatever the case, the detective won't forget her bloody past,
しかしまた後戻りするつもりもない。彼女はこれからも仲間とともに進む。
but she isn't going to revert to it either. She will continue to move forward with her friends,
望んだ結末を迎えられなかった別の自分たちのためににも。
and for all the variants who didn't get their desired ending.
探偵アーニャ・メルフィッサは、明日に向かって生き続ける。
The detective, Anya Melfissa, will keep on living for her own tomorrow.
Anya Melfissa Birthday Live 2023! Woo! How did everyone like it? Oh my goodness!
やっと今年も参りました、アーニャの誕生日です！いかがでしたでしょうか？
Finally, this year has come! It's Anya's birthday! How did you all like it?
This time, I tried to incorporate a little bit of story into my 3D birthday celebration, and I think it turned out pretty nice, you know?
You get story part and also live part, and I think it turned out pretty well!
You get a story part and also a live part, and I think it turned out pretty well!
And also, how was my new original song? Oh my goodness!
How was my new original song? It was good, wasn't it? I hope you all liked it!
新曲もね、あの、歌わせていただきました。いかがでしたでしょうか？
I also got to sing my new original song. How did you like it?
Oh my god, I celebrated... I celebrated my birthday with a lot of friends too this year. Yeah.
A lot of the girls came to celebrate my birthday, and also Detective Anya managed to solve that mission. Wow, she's got it.
Detective Anya... Did you guys like Detective Anya as well? Detective Anya was pretty cool, but not as cool as me!
Oh my god, and also special guests! There were special guests!
Oh my god, I can't believe I got to sing with Hatsune Miku! Hatsune Miku-chan!
Oh my god, she was really cute. And also for the narration for my story part, Ueda Reina-san narrated!
Oh my god! Ueda Reina-san also... Narration, the story part narration too, right? Ueda Reina-san...
...やってくれました！ありがとうございます！
...did it for me! Thank you so much!
美九ちゃんとも歌ったし、いや、盛りだくさんでしたね、今年。
I also sang with Miku-chan... It was really packed with content this year!
Oh my god, lots of wild things happening on this year's birthday live. How did you guys like it?
How did you guys like it? Oh my gosh, yeah, I had a lot of fun!
But! I would like to make an announcement this year. It's the usual.
ここで告知があります！I have an announcement to make! Let me make an announcement!
Here, I have an announcement! I have an announcement to make! Let me make an announcement!
はい、こちら！Oh my god! What is that? Who is that? Is that me? Yes, it is! We're releasing some new merchandises too this year!
Yes, this! Oh my god! What is that? Who is that? Is that me? Yes, it is! We're releasing some new merchandises too this year!
What do we have? Let's take a look at them, shall we? そして、えーと、一つずつ見ていきましょう。まずはこちらです！
What do we have? Let's take a look at them, shall we? And, well, let's look at them one by one. First is this!
Whoa, it's a canvas art! "Study Time with Anya" canvas art. Oh my god, this illustration is so cute! It's illustrated by Lunar-sensei!
Lunar先生にイラストを描いていただきました。可愛い！
Lunar-sensei drew this illustration for me. It's so cute!
The theme is, you know, literary girl. Oh my god, so smart! So intelligent! 文学少女というテーマになっております。
The theme is, you know, literary girl. Oh my god, so smart! So intelligent! The theme is a literary girl.
次はこちら！"Study Time with Anya" notebook! This is... I think this is my first notebook! I've never had a notebook as a merchandise before, oh my goodness!
Next is this! "Study Time with Anya" notebook! This is... I think this is my first notebook! I've never had a notebook as a merchandise before, oh my goodness!
Please use this lots for all your notes, for anything! いろいろメモしてね、オリジナルノートです。出ます。
Please use this lots for all your notes, for anything! Make lots of notes on it, it's an original notebook. It's coming out.
と、次はこちら。It's a pen case! How cute is that? ペンポーチです！ペンポーチも初かな？
And, next is this. It's a pen case! How cute is that? It's a pen pouch! Is it also my first pen pouch?
ノートも初らしい、ペンポーチもなんと、え、初です。ぜひ一緒にね、あのノートと使ってください。
The notebook is also a first, and the pen pouch is, wow, also a first. Please use it together with the notebook!
Um, use this along with the note. I think they would go really well together, okay?
次はこちら。今年もボイス出ます。そして今年も、え、アーニャが台本を書かせていただいております。
Next is this. A voice pack is coming out this year too. And this year too, Anya wrote the script.
I wrote the script as usual, as usual per every year. I wrote the script for this situational voice, so please get it! Please get it!
Oh yeah, the voice will be in Japanese but there will be scripts in Bahasa Indonesia, English and Japanese.
ちなみにボイス自体は日本語になりますけど、えーと、台本もついてきます。インドネシア語と英語と日本語の台本があります。
By the way, the voice itself will be in Japanese, but the script is also included. There are scripts in Indonesian, English, and Japanese.
ぜひ聞いてください。そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
Please listen to it. And here is the full set purchase bonus!
Oh my god! Limited Edition has... what is that? A hand-signed autograph? Oh my god, it's a first for me!
Anya's first ever hand-signed autograph for Limited Edition, please get them!
なんと今年はサイン入りです！今年はサイン入りです、なんと、なんと、なんと...
Unbelievably, this year it is hand-signed! This year it's hand-signed, wow, wow, wow...
...初！初ですね、アーニャが自らサインをして。初なので、ぜひ皆さん、この機会にゲットしてください。
...the first! It's the first time Anya signs it herself. Since it's the first time, everyone, please get it on this occasion!
Yeah, please get the Limited Edition! And for the Standard Edition, it includes a foil-stamped replica autograph, so don't worry if you miss out on the Limited Edition. Yay!
ということでグッズ紹介は以上です。That's all for the merch...
And that's all for the merchandise introduction. That's all for the merch...
...introduction!
And another announcement is that
my original song, the one that you guys heard...
It's called "Enka" or "ENCOUNT," by the way.
It will be releasing digitally!
It will be releasing digitally in like a few hours.
It will be releasing digitally at 12:00 AM your time zone, on March 13th!
Yay! Yippee!
So in like, in, in like a few hours, yeah.
Yay! なんとね、デジタルリリース、えー、新曲のデジタルリリースもあります！
Yay! Also, there will be a digital release, the digital release of my new song!
えー、13日の0時です。
It will be at midnight on March 13th.
よろしくお願いします！
I look forward to your support!
そしてこのあと、メンバーシップで配信もするのでぜひ見てください！
Also, I'll be streaming for members after this, so please check it out!
There will be a special encore for members only after this!
So, members, melhomies, let's go!
There will be a membership-only stream after this!
So please come and watch! It'll be, it will be in 3D, by the way.
So you guys might want to check it out.
Yippee!
Okay, are you guys ready? Are you guys ready? Well, this live is ending but we still have membership after this.
So, I will see you guys there! For members, I will see you guys there.
And for non-members, thank you so much for coming and for watching my 3D birthday live! I hope you guys enjoyed it!
Thank you! Thank you!
And I wonder if you guys also posted a lot using the hashtag. I sure hope you guys did!
Yay! Thank you so much!
And, otsu-cle! Bye-bye, otsu-cle everyone!